{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "What does digitalWrite(11, HIGH) do in this experiment?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Reads sensor value",
        "b": "Turns off relay",
        "c": "Turns on relay",
        "d": "Resets Arduino"
      },
    
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "What component is controlled by the relay in this circuit?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Sensor",
        "b": "LED",
        "c": "Motor",
        "d": "LCD"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	{
      "question": "Which function causes delay between relay switching?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "delay()",
        "b": "pause()",
        "c": "wait()",
        "d": "stop()"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	{
      "question": "How many terminals does a relay typically have (excluding coil)?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "2",
        "b": "3",
        "c": "4",
        "d": "6"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	{
      "question": "What is the function of NO (Normally Open) pin on the relay?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Always connected to COM",
        "b": "For power input",
        "c": "Ground connection",
        "d": "Connected only when coil is energized"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	{
      "question": "What will happen if you connect relay GND to 5V?",
      "answers": {
        "a": " Circuit wonâ€™t work",
        "b": "Relay works fine",
        "c": "LED glows permanently",
        "d": "Arduino restarts"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	{
      "question": "Why use a relay instead of directly driving an LED with Arduino?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "It's easier",
        "b": "For learning",
        "c": "Relay can handle higher loads",
        "d": "Saves code"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	{
      "question": "What happens when the relay coil is energized?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "NO connects to COM",
        "b": "Nothing",
        "c": "NC disconnects from COM",
        "d": "LED blinks randomly"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	{
      "question": "Which pin sends control signals to relay?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "GND",
        "b": "VCC",
        "c": "Analog pin 0",
        "d": "Digital pin 11"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	{
      "question": "What is the delay in the given code?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "500ms",
        "b": "1000ms",
        "c": "2000ms",
        "d": "No delay"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
  ]
}
